Guide to the NYU Abu Dhabi Memory Project Collection AD.RG.023
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Remote Interviews with NYUAD Community Members, April 2020 - July 2021
  - Interview session with Matteo Marciano, Toby Tinson, Ivan Budnik Pereira, Reema El Kaiali, Zain Mustafa, Goffredo Puccetti, (Gazelien Records) and Lauren Kata (01:25:05), 04 Mar 2021; ADRG023_033 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_033)
    Video-recorded session with Matteo Marciano, Toby Tinson, Goffredo Puccetti, Ivan Budnik, Reema Kaiali and Zain Mustafa, recorded on 4 March, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of the Memory Project.'
    This session is a "Part 2" follow up recording with the Gazelien Records 2021 team. They discuss their experience at the record label, specifically focusing on the various projects that they have worked on before and during the Covid-19 pandemic. Two main projects include their work with the Labcast, a podcast produced in collaboration with the NYU Production Lab, as well as the production of the song 'From a Balcony'. The team mentions the various ways in which they adapted to produce works even with limited equipment and space, and participants in different locations. They also refer to their connections with the studio, to community members across campuses, and to NYUAD community musicians.
  - Interview session with Muhammad Usman and Lauren Kata (01:23:26), 11 Mar 2021; ADRG023_034 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_034)
    Video-recorded session with Muhammad Usman, Security Officer for Public Safety, recorded on Thursday, 11 March, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, Muhammad Usman reflects on his journey to NYU Abu Dhabi, from starting a job at a computer assembly store in Islamabad, Pakistan, to dropping his passion for studying and applying for G4S, learning the mandatory training and getting a position as a security officer at NYUAD -- a university he was initially drawn to because of great working conditions. He shares his story of the NYUAD interview process, working at the Downtown Campus at the CSE Lab, daily happenings (for example, handling all the keys to the doors on the campus instead of having the current master key) and the first few weeks adjusting to Arabic culture after hearing experiences from his father, uncle and cousins who worked in Saudi Arabia. Throughout the interview, he shares anecdotes that happened during his work as a security officer. Most importantly, Muhammad explains how at NYUAD, he feels respected both as a person and as an employee. He emphasizes that people are not discriminated against based on their job position, rather there is mutual respect in the NYUAD community. He adds that while working in different places on the campus, he loves working in the Library, because he gets to communicate with students through different greeting styles.
  - Interview session with Anas Muhammad, Yaghsha Mir, Rameen Mahmood, Shehryar Hanif, and Jais Johnson Katoor (Library and IT Committee of NYUAD's Student Government AY 2019-2020) and Lauren Kata (54:54), 19 Mar 2021; ADRG023_035 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_035)
    Video-recorded session with Library and IT Committee of NYUAD's Student Government (Anas Muhammad, Yaghsha Mir, Rameen Mahmood, Shehryar Hanif, and Jais Johnson Katoor) recorded on Friday, 19 March, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project, during a 2021 "Memory Project Week."
    In this interview, the members of the Library and IT Committee start by sharing their own reasons for joining the committee - personal impact of the Library, the applicability of Library and IT elements in a remote environment, improving connectivity conditions for students, etc. Then, they reflect on their current work in the committee - from network connectivity to print services to software products, these members work on solving these concerns and providing equal opportunities for all students - and the future plans in terms of programming and organizing events. The Library and IT Committee members later explain their challenges with working in a remote environment and how they overcame these for themselves and for others through their work in the committee. Lastly, the members highlight how the work they do feels more important than ever because with online classes and other activities, with time, students are realizing the full potential of the internet to their benefit, and that the role of the committee is to aid every student in their remote journey to make a more accessible environment for all.
  - Interview session with Mbiko Mayaka and Lauren Kata (27:29), 20 Mar 2021; ADRG023_037 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_037)
    Video-recorded session with Mbiko Mayaka, NYU Abu Dhabi Class of 2023, recorded on Saturday, 20 March, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project, during a 2021 "Memory Project Week."
    Mbiko Mayaka, NYUAD Class of 2023 from Zambia, Social Research and Public Policy major, shares details about her life before coming to NYUAD and after. Mbiko learned about NYUAD through a former student of the American International School who also studied at the NYUAD. By attending the American International School, Mbiko learned the importance of intercultural communication. Mbiko shares how bringing her experiences from home enabled her to draw connections between NYUAD and home. She talks about different cultural celebrations - Afrofest and Diwali, the classes she has taken - Khaleeji Music, Cultural Appropriation, Street Food, Arab music, Art of the Personal Essay, as well as kayaking, going to the beach, going into the city, trying different cuisines, and how her entire experience is a highlight. Focusing on the present moment enabled Mbiko to make the most out of her experience at the University.
  - Interview session with Nurpeiis Baimukan, Jonathan Lee (Jagged) and Lauren Kata (40:08), 20 Mar 2021; ADRG023_038 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_038)
    Video-recorded session with Jonathan Lee and Nurpeiis Baimukan, NYU Abu Dhabi Class of 2021 and Jagged founders, recorded on Saturday, 20 March, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Librarian for Archives and Special Collections atNYUAD Library. Conducted as part of the Memory Project, during a 2021 "Memory Project Week."
    In this session, Nurpeiis and Jonathan talk about their first impressions of NYU Abu Dhabi, what inspired them to start Jagged, the importance of mentorship in their lives, and participation in the StartAD competition. Jagged is an online platform that matches high school students with mentors that are from university. Initially, it started off as a mentorship program in Kazakhstan and Malaysia. Nurpeiis mentions how attending Nazarbayev Intellectual School and completing the IB program shaped his personality, and after coming to NYUAD, he wanted to give back to the community. After his sophomore year, Nurpeiis and his friends, fellow students from Kazakhstan, started an Izbasar mentorship program. Jonathan also shares Nurpeiis' sentiments, and after seeing the success of the mentorship program with 20 paired mentors and mentees in Kazakhstan, they expanded the program to Malaysia and renamed it to Jagged. Together with their friends, Alex Edwards and Dhabia Al Mansoori, the team pitched their idea at StartAD and NYU New York Venture competitions and also received funding from Sandooq Al Watan. Currently they have launched their first app on the App Store and developed a Jagged podcast.
  - Interview session with Robert Titus, Norca Vincent, and Lauren Kata (01:25:28), 24 Mar 2021; ADRG023_039 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_039)
    Video-recorded session with Robert Titus, Director of the Department of Public Safety, and Norca Vincent, Assistant Director, recorded on Wednesday, 24 March, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    Robert Titus and Norca Vincent explain their journey to NYUAD and to the UAE -- the transition from New York, new experiences in Abu Dhabi, trips to the other Emirates, and their responsibilities in the Department of Public Safety. Both Robert and Norca explain how they adjusted to the NYUAD and UAE culture. They elaborate on the first few months of the outset of NYUAD -- they use the metaphor of a blank canvas -- highlighting the journey of Sama Tower and the first NYUAD campus, and integrating the staff workers. They talk about community adaptation both after the Sama fire, and in building stronger relationships with the people employed by the Department. Lastly, both Norca and Robert discuss the firsts -- first Candidate Weekend, first class, first Marhaba and more, as well as how the sense of community was built. Lastly, as most important milestones throughout the years, Norca reflects on the efforts of the NYUAD administration to include more African American and Latino contract staff, permanent employees, professors, while Robert reflects on collective work to enlarge the capacities to fit within the frame of the bigger Saadiyat Campus.
  - Interview session with Alex Ko, Jakub Jurkovic, Emília Vieira Branco, Lucas Davidenco (Anchorage), and Lauren Kata (01:21:39), 26 Mar 2021; ADRG023_040 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_040)
    Video-recorded session with Alex Ko, Emília Vieira Branco, Jakub Jurkovic, Lucas Davidenco and Dino Kolonić, members of the Anchorage E-Board, recorded on 26 March, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    Four members of the Anchorage E-Board discuss their individual journeys with Anchorage, as well as the role of the SIG in the NYUAD community. They describe important events that they have held over Zoom such as Spooky Speed Dating, as well as long-standing events such as the Family Dinner. With some emotion, they discuss a moment of tension in the community when an article was published in the school newspaper The Gazelle. The team also reflects on the future, including the future role of Anchorage in the community and changes in the UAE.
  - Interview session with Tori Mondello, Morgane Motlik and Mate Hekfusz (53:14), 16 Mar 2021; ADRG023_041 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_041)
    Video-recorded Memory Project session with NYUAD students Tori Mondello and Morgane Motlik, recorded on Tuesday, March 16, 2021, and facilitated by Mate Hekfusz, a NYUAD student. Conducted and self-submitted to be added to The Memory Project collection.
    In this interview, three friends (classmates) are sharing their NYUAD journey and campus experiences. Firstly, they start by sharing how they met each other, their Marhaba experiences and adjustment to campus life. Then, they speak about their engagements outside class: including SIGs, volunteering, assistantships, and birthdays. They share anecdotes about choosing NYUAD and their instantaneous family support/response. Mate and Morgane also talk about their schooling and their concern about their English accent, which they realize, it's not really a problem at NYUAD. Also, they talk about their off-campus travel, and assignment pressures. They also express their optimism for their senior year and their future career plans. They conclude on a message from the future to one another.
  - Interview session with Katarina Holtzapple, Zhong (Zack) Chen, Jay Lee, Simran Motiani, Kamel Alsharif (REACH), and Lauren Kata (01:14:19), 27 Apr 2021; ADRG023_042 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_042)
    Video-recorded session with Katarina Holtzapple, Zhong (Zack) Chen, Jay Lee, Simran Motiani, Kamel Alsharif, REACH members, recorded on Tuesday, 27 April, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of the Memory Project.
    REACH stands for Raising Empowered Advocates for Community Health, and was founded by Kamel Alsharif, Annalisa Galgano, and Eliza T. in 2015 under the supervision of Tina Wadhwa (Student Success and Well Being). In 2015, Kamel Alsharif, Class of 2017, noticed that there were not enough mental health support services for students (no professional counselors at the Health and Wellness Center), and following the mentality "See something - say something", he started REACH together with his friends. While REACH has an element of SIG (Student Interest Group) to it, such as students having interest in supporting mental health development, it exists outside of the SIG framework. The recruitment process for REACH members has changed and evolved over time, as well as the number of students who want to join REACH. REACH members take up different roles, including but not limited to: The Nook (peer-counseling service), social media (looking over social media accounts), treasurer (managing the budget), leading the group (training students). REACH is unique to NYU Abu Dhabi, and has played an integral role in debunking stereotypes about mental health. REACH also organizes so-called "legacy" events yearly, such as ordering banana pudding or bubble tea for the entire community, and hosting Doggy De-Stress. The nature of the event changes based on the health and safety regulations. Katarina Holtzapple, Class of 2020, also notes how the demographics among the REACH members has evolved over time, with more students from different backgrounds, such as Computer Science, joining the team.
  - Interview session with Tina Wadhwa, Annalisa Galgano, Liza Tait-Bailey, Nadeen Alalami (REACH), and Lauren Kata (01:28:29), 30 Apr 2021; ADRG023_043 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_043)
    Video-recorded session with Tina Wadhwa, Director of Student Success and Wellbeing, Annalisa Galgano, Liza Tait-Bailey, Nadeen Alalami, former REACH members, recorded on Friday, 30 April, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    REACH stands for Raising Empowered Advocates for Community Health, and was founded by Kamel Alsharif, Annalisa Galgano, and Eliza T. in 2015 under the supervision of Tina Wadhwa (Student Success and Well Being). This is Session 2 of 3 interview sessions about REACH.
    Tina, Annalisa, Liza, and Nadeen share how they became a part of NYU Abu Dhabi, but also how they began working in REACH (Annalisa and Liza were part of the founding group for REACH). Annalisa explains how the REACH team wanted the program to have a holistic approach of student mental health and wellbeing, and then in conversation with Liza, discusses the importance of being there for one another and having the vision of starting a program. Then, Tina shares the story of the Mission and Vision activity during the conceptualization phase, and how the students were so engaged and proactive and how that activity impacted the narrative of the program for the future. Later on, everyone explains their perception of REACH's origin story - from the first few meetings and events, peer support activities and sessions, budget difficulties, low outreach, to continual progress and REACH becoming a household name. Then, all of them reflect on their mission to push for change and advocate for different things while supporting peers. Tina touches upon the skills that students acquire: validating, normalizing, refraining; also she discusses the intercept between the Health Promotion Office and REACH. Finally, everyone discusses how the impact of REACH remains with them after graduating, and that they carry REACH values with them throughout life.
  - Interview session with Abdur Rehman, Dana AlHosani, Rida Zafar, Brian Kim (REACH), and Lauren Kata (57:25), 02 May 2021; ADRG023_044 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_044)
    Video-recorded Memory Project session with former REACH members Abdur Rehman, Dana AlHosani, Rida Zafar, and Brian Kim, recorded on Sunday, May 2, 2021, and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    REACH stands for Raising Empowered Advocates for Community Health, and was founded by Kamel Alsharif, Annalisa Galgano, and Eliza T. in 2015 under the supervision of Tina Wadhwa (Student Success and Well Being). This is Session 3 of 3 interview sessions about REACH.
    In this interview, Brian (current student) and three alumni -- Abdur Rehman, Dana AlHosani, and Rida Zafar -- share their experiences working with REACH. They start by explaining the significance and origin story of REACH. All of them restate that REACH is a student-led peer support initiative which mainly focuses on the physical and mental well-being of the community. Brian shares his experience on being a part of REACH from his freshman year. He also recalls the emergence of REACH from a limited role in the Health Promotion Office to an integral part of campus life and independent student body. Dana shares why she was intimidated to join REACH initially, but later with the help of Tina Wadhwa (from Health Promotion Office), she practiced role-playing and active listening that earned her a position in the REACH during her senior year. Rida talks about the most impressive programs of REACH; redefining success and anonymous failures in which different success and failure stories beyond academics are shared, and encourages students to look for their own successes and handle failures. Abdur talks about the other works of REACH, such as delivering Safe Alcohol Education, Sexual Misconduct, and Administrative meetings. In between, they also talk about their experience helping people with stress management, hosting Nook sessions (peer counselling) and their attachment with people both in and out of REACH.
- Office of Social Responsibility - Partner Interviews, OSR 10th Anniversary Project, 2021
  Twenty-one (21) audio recorded interviews conducted and recorded by PPPT researcher Laura Assanmal during the summer of 2021, she was a team member in the NYUAD Office of Social Responsibility, the project was part of a 10th anniversary reflection on contract colleagues who have been part of the NYUAD community for a decade or longer, and led to the editing and writing of a 10th anniversary OSR booklet.
  - Interview session with Hazel Lorena and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (38:38), 10 June 2021; ADRG023_045 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_045)
    Audio-recorded session with Hazel Lorena, recorded on [June 10, 2021] and facilitated by Laura Assanmal. Conducted as part of The Memory Project and as part of the Office of Social Responsibility's 10th Anniversary Book Project. The interview was conducted in-person. For the most part, there are only two people present at the interview site (the interviewer and interviewee), but at certain times, there are people passing by in the background.
    In this interview session, Hazel Lorena shares her experiences and talks about the happiness brought by working abroad and at NYUAD, as well as about the challenges she faces. Hazel Lorena has been working at NYUAD since August, 2010 as a Public Safety Officer via G4S. Before coming to NYUAD, she lived in Manila, Philippines. She obtained her Bachelor's degree in Hotel and Restaurant Management, and upon graduation, she worked at Unilab, a pharmaceutical company in the Philippines. She later joined an agency in order to work abroad. She was 23 when she came to work in the Middle East and at the time of the interview had been working for 19 years. Lorena has previously worked as a receptionist at Montgomerie Golf Club in Dubai, as a waitress at a restaurant in Qatar, and later joined the security team at NYUAD. She shares her memories of the first class of NYUAD at Sama Tower and adult education classes offered by the Office of Social Responsibility. Despite the challenges, Hazel Lorena is very glad to be a member of the NYUAD community and regards NYU as one big family.
  - Interview session with Serkalem Bekele Admasse and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (14:55), 8 June 2021; ADRG023_046 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_046)
    Audio-recorded Memory Project session with Public Safety (G4S) officer, Serkalem Bekele, recorded on the 8th of June, 2021, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, a PPTP student for the Office of Social Responsibility and conducted as part of OSR's 10-year project and The Memory Project. The interview was conducted in-person. For the most part, there are only two people present at the interview site (the interviewer and interviewee), but at certain times, there are people passing by in the background.
    In this interview, Serkalem Bekele, Public Safety (G4S) officer, shares her family story, work life, and her journey to NYUAD. She starts by talking about her home (Ethiopia), family, languages she speaks (Amharic, English, Arabic) and her education background (Computer Engineering). Then, she shares about her first arrival to the UAE back in 2005. She mentions about her jobs in different places like Dubai Mall, Abu Dhabi University, the British Embassy and finally in NYUAD. Serkalem also talks about the changes she has seen at NYUAD from a small downtown Sama Tower campus to a huge Saadiyat campus with growing numbers of students and staff over the years. She also added motivating words that during difficult times we should not only focus on problems but on solutions and resolve them. In the end, she appreciates the working environment and the opportunities (language and life-skills courses) provided by OSR for their holistic development.
  - Interview session with Fathia Omar and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (17:23), 8 June 2021; ADRG023_047 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_047)
    Audio-recorded session with Fathia Omar, Controlling Supervisor, recorded on Tuesday, June 8, 2021, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 Year Project/Memory Project Partnership. The interview took place on the ground floor of C2, in front of the Office for Social Responsibility in NYU Abu Dhabi. There are two people present at the interview site - the interviewer and interviewee. There is slight background noise at 03:35, perhaps from Fathia's co-workers.
    Fathia describes her work in the camera control room and the role of a supervisor in the Security Office; her origin story of Berbera, Somalia, and the UAE; her language skills: Somali, English, Arabic, and her education, which was in UAE government schools, allowing her to get immersed in the Arabic culture. Regarding her journey to NYU Abu Dhabi — a friend told her that G4S is hiring, and she started in Al Ain, but then got invited to join NYUAD in 2010, and got interviewed by Mr. Robert Titus and Ms. Norca Vincent, getting accepted in the end. She wanted to work at NYUAD because she wanted to become independent and responsible — the support from her family helped her along the way. What she likes about the NYUAD community is that she met wonderful, diverse people, but a challenge has been the separation from her family. Lastly, Fathia reflects on possible plans for the future, which for her are studying in medical school to become a phlebotomist.